大家好，能听到我的声音吗？
Hi, can everyone hear me okay?
好的，欢迎回到你们的计算机科学教育中缺失的学期。
Okay, so welcome back to the missing semester of your CS education,
今天我们的讲座主题是“杂项”。
today we're having as a lecture topic "potpourri".
这将是一些
It's gonna be some miscellaneous combination of topics
我们讲师认为有趣
that we the instructors find that are interesting.
但又不足以成为单独讲座的主题的组合。
But none of them were on their own lecture
但是它们都是我们希望你们知道的一些特定主题，
because they're certain topics that we just want you to know about,
因为它们可能非常有用。
because they can be really helpful
由于我们不会详细探讨这些主题，
And since we're not gonna delve into a lot of detail in the topics.
如果你对它们更感兴趣，
If you're more interested about them just feel free to come
可以随时在讲座结束后或讲座期间向我们提问。
and ask us questions at the end or as we go over them in the lecture.
所以我想先谈谈键盘重新映射。
So the first thing I want to talk about is keyboard re-mappings/
到现在为止，你可能已经意识到
So by now you probably realized that
我们鼓励你使用键盘作为主要的输入方法。
we have encouraged you to use the keyboard as your main input method.
例如，当我们进入编辑器讲座时，
So for example, when we went into the editors lecture,
Vim 的一个主要思想就是尽可能多地使用键盘。
one of the main ideas of Vim was using your keyboard as much as possible.
这样你就不必依赖鼠标，
So you don't have to rely on going to the mouse
因为使用鼠标是慢的。
because going to the mouse is slow
事实上，你的键盘，就像电脑中的许多其他东西一样，
And the thing is your keyboard, as with many things in your computer
都可以进行配置。
is nothing kind of magical, it can be configured
而且配置是值得的，因为许多默认设置可能不是最优的。
And it's worth configuring because a lot of the defaults might not be optimal
最简单的修改方法就是重新映射键。
The most simple modification that you can do is just to remap keys
例如，在编辑器讲座中我们提到，
So one of the things we alerted in the editor lecture
大写锁定键是一个非常好的键，
is the Caps Lock key is a really good key
因为它位于主键盘区，而且很大，
because it's kind of right in the home row and it's kind of large and there,
但它并没有什么用处。
but it's not useful
你可能会意识到
You'll probably realize that you don't use your Caps Lock
你不常使用大写锁定键。
as often as when you'd want to use that
因此，你可以将大写锁定键重新映射为更有用的键，
So you can just remap your Caps Lock key to something more useful
如 Escape（如果你是 Vim 用户）或 Control（如果你是 Emacs 用户）
as we mentioned like Escape if you're a Vim user or like Control if you're an Emacs user
或其他实用的重新映射，
or useful re-mappings,
如 F 功能键或 Print Screen。
like a lot of the upper row 'F' function keys, or like Print Screen
例如，你可以将它们重新映射为媒体键，这样当你按下 Print Screen 时，
You can remap them for example to your media key so like when you type Print Screen,
你可能不需要那么频繁地截屏，
you probably don't have to do Print Screen that often
但你可能需要播放或暂停音乐。
but you probably want to play or pause your music
几乎每个操作系统都有一些工具可以用来配置这些功能。
And pretty much every operating system has some tools that you can use to configure this
我不会详细介绍，但在注释中列出了其中一些。
I'm not gonna go into the details but there's some of them listed in the notes
哦，是的，你可以使用键盘重新映射来
Erm... Let me check Oh yeah, another thing that you can do with keyboard re-mappings is
执行更复杂的组合操作。
that you can do more complex combinations
你可以将一些键的组合映射到某些操作上。
You can have a combination of keys mapped to some action
例如，我有一些键盘重新映射，每当我按下 Ctrl+Enter 时，
So for example, I have keyboard re-mappings that whenever I do Ctrl+Enter,
就会打开一个新的终端窗口。
I open a new terminal window
因为这是我经常做的事情，
because that's a thing I do fairly often
并且在Mac上默认情况下没有绑定按键来执行该操作，
and by default on Mac there is no key binding to do that
或者Ctrl + Shift + Enter将打开一个新的浏览器窗口，
or Ctrl+Shift+Enter will open a new browser window,
这是我每天都要做的另一个操作。
another operation that I do on a daily basis
所以我不必拿起鼠标去Chrome执行它。
So I don't have to grab my mouse and go to Chrome to do that
你也可以重新映射来执行操作。
You can also do remapping to perform actions
如果你不想一直输入你的密码......
If you don't want to be typing your password all the...
不好意思，不是你的密码，是你的电子邮件或密码，
Sorry, not your password Your Email or your password,
或者例如你的MIT ID，你可能不记得它，
or for example, your MIT ID like, you may not remember it by heart
那么你可以有一个键盘组合键
then you can just have a keyboard combination
来执行粘贴文本的操作。
that will just perform the action of pasting that text
最后，还有更多...
Lastly, there are more...
现在看起来你只需要执行
Right now it looks like you just have to do some function of
“这是你按下的键和这是发生的动作”的功能。
"this is the keys that you press and this is the action that happens"
但实际上有更复杂的键盘组合键，
But actually there are more complex keyboard combinations,
当你不断学习时，你会发现你可以执行键盘序列。
and as you go through you'll learn so you can do keyboard sequences
所以例如当我们处理tmux时，
So for example when we were dealing with tmux,
在tmux中有这个概念，首先你按下Ctrl + A或Ctrl + B，
in tmux there was this notion of first you press Ctrl+A or Ctrl+B, like you press some prefix
就像你按下一些前缀然后一些其他的键，那意味着某些东西。
and then some other key and that means something
很多这些软件都允许这样做。
A lot of these softwares allow that
例如，在我的键盘上，因为我根本不使用Caps Lock，
So for example, in my keyboard, since I'm not using Caps Lock at all,
但偶尔我的本科生有一些
but every so often I have to use when my undergrad has some software that
依赖Caps Lock更改模式的软件。
relied on Caps Lock for changing modes
然后我可以快速连续按五次Shift键，
Then I can press Shift five times in a row quickly, and then
然后处于中间的解释这些命令
this software that is in the middle interpreting these commands
并重新映射到其他命令的软件将为此发送一个单独的Caps Lock命令。
and remapping to some other, will send a single Caps Lock command for that
更多的例子是
Some more examples of that is that
我提到你可以使用你的Caps Lock键映射到Escape或Control，
I mentioned that you can use your Caps Lock key to map to Escape or Control
但实际上你可以重新映射它们两个。
but you actually can remap it to both
所以在我的电脑上，当我轻按Caps Lock键时，它被解释为Escape。
So in my computer when I just tap the Caps Lock key, that's interpreted as an Escape
然而，如果我按住它，
However if I press it and hold it,
这个软件可以理解快速按下它
this software can understand the difference between quickly pressing it and
和仅仅按住它以与其他键组合使用的区别，
just holding it for using in combination with some other key
然后在这种情况下它被映射到Control。
and then in that case it's mapped to Control
很多这些更高级的配置都得到了许多这些工具的支持。
So a lot of these more advanced configurations are supported on a lot of these tools
正如我所提到的，我们有一个关于Windows、Mac OS和Linux的
As I mentioned we have a short list of good defaults
这些程序的良好默认值的简短列表。
for these programs for Windows, Mac OS and Linux
这个话题有什么问题吗？
Any questions on this topic?
好的，现在我要讲解一个与键盘映射无关的话题
Okay, now I'm going to cover an unrelated topic to keyboard mappings
我们将在本讲座中看到许多这些不相关的过渡。
We're going to see a lot of these unrelated transitions in this lecture
这就是“守护进程”的概念。
And it's the concept of "daemons"
所以你可能......
So probably you have...
也许如果你不熟悉这个领域，这个概念看起来很陌生，
Maybe if you are not familiar with the world, it might seem alien,
但你对守护进程这个概念应该已经很熟悉了。
but the concept of daemon you're pretty familiar with
大多数计算机在运行时会启动和运行一些软件，
Most computers when you are running them there's software that you start and run,
就像我们一直在看到的那些命令一样，
like the commands that we have been seen
比如输入“ls”，就是调用“列出文件列表”命令。
You'd type "ls" and then you're calling the ls command
"ls"命令执行
The "ls" command executes
是因为你要求它执行，然后它就完成了。
because you asked it to execute and then it finishes
但是许多其他程序只是作为后台进程运行，
But a lot of other programs are just running as background processes
它们只是在后台执行并等待事件发生
and they're just executing in the background and waiting for events to happen
或启用计算机的某些功能。
or enabling some sort of functionality in your computer
这些进程的示例
Examples of these processes may be like your Network Man
可能包括像网络管理器这样的部分，
like the part of your computer that is managing the network
或者像管理显示的计算机部分。
or the part of your computer that is managing the display
您会发现，守护进程启用的大多数内容
Things like that you will see that a lot of what is enabled by daemons
通常是以'd'结尾的程序。
is usually programs that end with a 'd'
例如，当您通过SSH连接到计算机时，
So for instance, when you are SSHing into a computer,
接收计算机必须具有SSH守护进程，
the receiving computer has to have a SSH daemon
该程序称为"sshd"，
and the program is called "sshd"
如果此程序未运行，则无法通过SSH连接到计算机。
and if this program is not running then there's no way for me to SSH into the computer
如果该程序正在运行，
If the program is running,
则该程序将正在侦听，当您SSH到该服务器时，
then that program will be listening and when you do SSH to that server,
一些传入请求将进入计算机，
then some incoming request is gonna enter the computer
计算机将将其发送到在后台运行的该守护进程，
the computer is gonna send it to this daemon that is running in the background
然后该守护进程将检查您是否有授权，
and then the daemon is gonna check whether you have authorization,
如果有，则将启动一些登录Shell，以便您可以开始执行。
and if so, it's gonna start some login shell that you can start executing from
不同的操作系统处理此问题的方式有所不同，
And different OSes handle this somewhat differently
但它们都有某种响应
The main idea is they all have some sort of
这些较小守护进程的系统守护进程。
system daemon that responds a lot of these smaller daemons
在我们为许多示例选择的Linux中，。
In Linux, which is one of the OSes that we are choosing for lot of the examples,
您正在使用的工具是"systemd"
the tool that you're using is the "systemd"
首先，系统守护进程将启动许多这些进程，
Again, first the system daemon is gonna start a lot of these processes
如果您使用"systemctl"命令，
and if you use this "systemctl" command,
则可以检查不同守护进程的状态，
you can check for the status of different daemons
您可以检查哪些正在运行，
you can check for which ones are running,
可以要求它启动进程或停止它们。
you can ask it to start processes, to stop them
这是一种一次性的操作。
This is kind of an once-off operation
您还可以启用它，然后禁用它们，
You can also enable it and then disable them,
这将告诉系统在启动时运行它们
which will tell the system to run them at boot
或停止启动它们。
or stop running the boot if they were enabled
更有趣的是，您可以配置自己的"systemd"单位。
And perhaps more interestingly, you can configure your own "systemd" units
到目前为止，所有示例都是计算机必须执行的许多内容，
So, so far all the examples are a lot of what the computer has to do,
但是假设您想运行Web服务器。
but say you want to run a web server.
一个解决方案是，
One solution, you could just like,
您可以每次启动计算机时打开tmux会话，
every time you start your computer you could open a tmux session
然后执行命令，
and then execute the command,
但这不是计算机期望守护进程运行的方式。
but that's not really the way that your computer expects daemons to be run
计算机期望守护进程运行的方式是使用某种"systemd"单位。
The way your computer expects daemons to be run is by using some sort of "systemd" unit
这是一种告诉"systemd"如何执行此进程的配置。
It's like a configuration that tells "systemd" how to execute this process
这个的一个简单例子是：
So an example of this is... Here's a very simple example
这里发生的事情是我们正在向"systemd"描述
So what is happening here is we're describing to "systemd"
需要执行此程序的步骤。
what needs to be done for this program to execute.
这个例子只是运行一个简单的Python应用程序，
This example is just running a simple Python app
你可以将其视为
You can think of it as a web server
使用某些Python Web服务器库实现的Web服务器。
that can be implemented using some Python web server library.
我们在这里说的是这个描述，
And here we're saying this is the description,
我们说在某个之后，像这样很重要，
we're saying after, like this is important
"Systemd"有一个必须启动的服务列表，
"Systemd" has a list of services that have to start
像所有这些守护进程都必须启动，
Like, all these daemons have to be started
但是可能存在这些守护进程之间的依赖关系，
but maybe there are dependencies between these daemons,
所以我们在这里说"不，只有在网络设置完成后才能启动此服务"，
so here we're saying "no, you should only start this after the network has been set up"
因为否则，如果我无法侦听网络端口，
because otherwise how will you even try to configure our web server
你甚至如何尝试配置我们的Web服务器呢？
if I cannot listen to a network port?
然后我们定义了应该运行此服务的用户，
And then we are defining what users should run this,
因为你可能想要将其作为自己的用户运行，或者可能是其他用户，
because you may want to run this as your user, or maybe other user,
或者可能是root用户在运行此服务，
or maybe the root user should be running this,
然后定义了要运行的命令和在哪个目录下运行。
and then what command to run and under what directory
当你有这个时，
And whenever you have this,
可能会有一些小的角落情况需要调试，
there can be small corner cases that you might have to debug,
但这是核心思想，
but this is kind of the core idea
可以非常有用地自动化后台运行进程的过程。
and it can be really useful to automate the process of running processes in the background
对此的一个小侧面说明是
A small side note to this
，如果你只想定期运行一个命令，
is the fact that if you just want to run a command every so often, like in some periodicity,
比如每天早上我都想在我的计算机上做一些事情，
say every morning I want to do something in my computer,
你可以编写一个守护进程，它只做一些事情然后睡觉一天，
you could write a daemon that just does something and then sleeps for a day,
但实际上Linux和Mac OS已经有了一个这样做的守护进程，称为"crond"，
but actually Linux and Mac OS have already a daemon that does this called "crond"
"crond"将采用另一种类型的配置文件，
and "crond" will take another type of configuration file
你可以说哦，我想在每天上午8点运行一个命令，
where you can say oh, I want to run a command every day at 8 AM,
或者我想每5分钟运行一个命令，
or I want to run a command every 5 minutes,
它将只检查此事件并执行它。
and it will just check for this event and execute it
对于许多事情，你会发现
And with a lot of things you will find that
已经配置了相应的守护进程。
there are already daemons that have been configured for that
有关守护进程的任何问题吗？
Any questions regarding daemons?
问题是是否有一个计算机上的文件夹，其中包含所有这些配置文件？
So the question is whether there is a folder in the computer where all of these are
是和不是，
So yeah, like yes and no
这些配置文件中的一些位于几个不同的文件夹中，
Some of these configuration files are in a couple of different folders
具体取决于它们是系统守护进程还是用户守护进程。
depending on whether they are system daemons or they are user daemons
在这里，您可以看到在第一行的位置是将此放置在系统守护进程中
Here you can see at the very first line is where you will place this
以便其被识别为已安装的位置，
for the system daemon to recognize that it has been installed
但是如果您只想列出正在运行的所有守护进程，
but if you just want to list all the daemons that are running,
则例如在Linux中，您只需执行“systemctl status”，
in Linux for example, you can just do "systemctl status"
它将打印出所有系统的树状结构，
and that's gonna print a tree of all the systems
以及哪个守护进程是由哪个其他守护进程产生的，
and which daemon was spawned by which other daemon
其中许多直接由“systemd”生成。
and a lot of them will be spawned directly by "systemd"
下一个话题将是用户空间的文件系统，
The next topic is going to be file systems in user space
所以，对此进行快速介绍的事实是，每当您使用现代操作系统时...
So, kind of a quick intro to this is the fact that whenever you're using a modern..
哦，对不起，还有一件事，每当您使用现代操作系统时...
Oh, yeah, sorry... And whenever you're using a modern operating system,
你不必局限于特定的文件系统。
you are not tied to a specific file system
现代系统相当模块化，
So modern systems are fairly modular and you can for example,
例如在Linux中有不同的文件系统可供选择。
in Linux there are different file systems that you can use,
这是因为
and the way this works is because the kernel,
内核是运行大部分操作系统的程序，
which is what is running most of the operating system,
有一些模块知道如何与文件系统进行交互。
has some modules that know how to interact with a file system
通常，当你执行像"touch foobar"这样的命令时，
So usually when you do something like "touch foobar",
这是在用户级别进行的，
this is happening at a user level
然后通过内核级别，
and then this is going through to the kernel level
并有一层检查在这个操作发生的位置，
and there is some kind of layer here that is checking
以确定它属于哪个文件系统。
where this action is happening to figure out what file system it is under
例如，你将拥有多个磁盘，
So for example, you will have multiple disks
每个磁盘都有不同的文件系统，
and all the different disks have different file systems,
因此内核必须确定要使用哪个文件系统操作，
so the kernel has to figure out which file system operations to use,
并说这个文件可能在一个"Ext4"文件系统中，这是最常见的Linux文件系统之一。
and say this file might be in an "Ext4", which is the most common Linux one,
那么，每当你执行"touch foobar"时，
then whenever you do "touch foobar", the kernel will hear that
内核会听到并试图找出它属于Ext4文件系统，
and then it will try to figure out like, oh, this lives in an Ext4 file system
然后执行创建文件的相关指令。
and it will perform the associated instruction for creating a file in an Ext4 file system
然而，这种系统的缺点是
However, the caveat of having a system like this is right now
现在我不能拥有定义如何创建文件的用户代码，
I cannot have user code that defines how to create a file
在某些情况下这可能会很有用。
and that might be kind of useful in some cases
比如说，我想拥有一个文件系统，每次有人创建文件时，
Say I want to have a file system that every time someone creates a file,
它会给我发送一封电子邮件，这样我就可以知道人们正在创建这些文件。
it sends me an email, so I can know that people are creating these files
但是在这里我无法修改内核来添加这个功能。
Here I cannot modify the kernel to add this
解决这个问题的方法叫做"FUSE"，
So the solution to this is something called "FUSE"
FUSE是一种在用户空间中拥有文件系统的方法。
And FUSE is a way of having file systems in user space
因此，如果这个文件不是在Ext4中，
So what FUSE will do is, if this file instead of being in Ext4,
而是在FUSE文件系统中，
if this file is in a FUSE file system,
FUSE将把这个操作转发到用户调用的某个其他部分，
FUSE will forward this operation to some other part of user call
该部分将说"哦，创建这个文件"。
that will say "oh, create this file"
在这里，我可以拥有发送电子邮件给我的代码部分，
And here I can have the part of the code that sends an email to me,
告诉我"哦，这个文件已经被创建了"。
saying "oh, this file has been created"
如果你仍然想创建该文件，
And in case you want to still create the file,
它可以把请求转发回来，做一些更多的内核操作。
it can forward back the request to do some more kernel operations
这似乎并不是很实用，
It might not seem really practical,
但这只是理论上的。在实践中，这很有用，
but this is just the theory. In practice, why this is useful is because
因为现在你可以在尝试执行文件系统操作时
now you can have user level code that executes arbitrary actions
执行任意动作的用户级代码。
when you try to perform file system operations
一个非常有趣的例子是"FUSE"
A really Interesting example of this is called "SSHFS"
So SSHFS ????  whenever you try...
在一个SSHFS FUSE文件系统上，无论你尝试创建、打开、读取、写入一个文件，
On an SSHFS FUSE file system, whenever you try to create, open, read, write to a file,
它都会通过SSH连接到远程服务器，
instead of trying to do that to a local file,
而不是尝试在本地文件上执行操作。
it has an SSH connection to a remote server
因此，如果我在这里尝试创建一个文件，
So if I try to create a file here,
它将使用SSH连接将该操作转发到远程系统，
It will use that SSH connection to forward that operation to the remote system
然后在那里执行。
and then it will perform it there
因此，在我的本地计算机上，
So to all my local computer,
在运行的其他程序中，
to the rest of the programs running in my computer,
有一个路径看起来好像它在这里，
there is this path that looks like it is here,
但是对路径执行的所有操作都被转发到远程文件系统。
but all the operations that are performed to the path are forwarded to the remote file system
基于这个想法，你会在笔记中找到一些例子，
And with this idea, you will get some examples in the notes,
并在线上找到更多，
and you will find more online,
说明人们如何利用这种能力来创建相当有趣的文件系统。
of ways people have leveraged this capability to do fairly interesting file systems
例如，如果你不关心SSH，
So for example, if instead of having SSH,
因为你使用Dropbox或Google Drive，
you don't care about SSH because you use Dropbox or Google Drive,
那么人们已经实现了FUSE文件系统，可以在本地挂载，
it's fine, people have implemented FUSE file systems that will mount locally
每次你尝试在本地执行操作时，
and every time you try to do an operation locally,
实际上它会去这些云存储提供商之一，
actually it goes to one of these cloud storage providers
所以你也可以使用像Amazon S3
so you can also use something like Amazon S3,
或Google Cloud Storage这样的服务，
or Google Cloud Storage, that don't have the same kind of UI system
它们没有像Dropbox或Google Drive那样的同步UI系统。
that we synchronize, as Dropbox or Google Drive
这种方法的另一个应用与远程操作无关，
Another application of this that is not related to doing something remotely,
就是加密文件系统。
is something like an encrypted file system
你可能有一个文件系统，每次你尝试写入一个文件时，
You may have a file system that every time you try to write to a file,
你都会尝试以明文形式写入它，
you will try to write it in plain text,
但它会捕获该操作，动态地加密它，
but it will capture that operation it will encrypt on the go,
然后将其保存为常规文件在你的文件系统中，但实际上是加密的。
and then it will save it as a regular file in your file system, but that's actually encrypted
一旦你卸载文件系统，一旦你断开FUSE连接，
And once you dismount the file system, once you remove the FUSE connection,
你的计算机上只剩下一些加密的常规文件。
all that is left in your computer are just regular files that are encrypted
我想要讨论的最后一个主题是备份和一些关于它们的良好做法。
The last topic I wanna cover is backups and some good practices about them
主要的想法是，对于你关心的每个文件，
The main idea is that for every file that you care about,
如果你没有备份它，
if you don't have a backup of that file,
如果你没有存储它的备份，你几乎可以在任何时候失去它。
if you don't have a backup stored of that file, you can pretty much lose it at any moment
有许多不同的故障场景。
There are many different failure scenarios
其中之一就是硬件故障。
One of them is just hardware failure.
所以你的硬盘可能在任何时刻都会出现故障。
So your hard drive can fail at any moment
因此，如果你只是在同一个驱动器上复制你的文件，那是没有用的。
So if you are just making a copy of your files in the same drive, that's not useful
如果你的硬盘故障了，文件就丢失了。
If your hard drive fails, the files are gone
如果你在外部驱动器上进行备份，
The same goes if you have an external drive where you are making a copy,
但是如果你把所有东西都存储在你的家里，而你的家着火了......
but if you are storing everything in your home, and your home burns down...
这虽然不太可能，但如果发生了，你就失去了所有的数据。
Which yes, it's unlikely, but if it happens you just lost all your data
因此你需要有一个离线备份的解决方案。
So you'd have some sort of off-site backup for having this solution
还要注意的一件事是同步或镜像选项不是备份。
Another thing to take into account is that synchronization or mirroring options are not backups
所以像我之前提到的 Google Drive 和 Dropbox
So Google Drive, Dropbox that I was mentioning,
只会传播你电脑上发生的任何事情。
they will just propagate whatever is happening in your computer
这也适用于硬件镜像，如 RAID。
This goes also for hardware mirroring, like RAID
它们只是在制作副本。如果你不小心删除了一个文件，
They are just making a copy If you accidentally delete a file,
或者有人恶意删除了你的文件，或者使用某些勒索软件对它们进行加密，
or someone maliciously deletes your files, or encrypts them using some ransomware,
那么你可能会有一个副本，但你只有一份无用的数据副本。
then you might have a copy, but you have a copy of the same useless data
你必须拥有备份运行的解决方案。
You actually have to have a solution of how you're running your backups
你应该问自己，
And you should be asking yourself
有什么人需要知道或拥有你的信息才能删除你所有的数据。
what actually someone needs to know/have about you in order to delete all your data
我们在笔记中链接了不同的软件，介绍了如何备份。
And we have linked different softwares in the notes about how to do this
最后我要提到的是备份时，
The last thing I want to mention about backups is that
很多时候你只会考虑本地文件，
a lot of the time when you think about backups, you just think about the local files
比如所有的照片和报税申报表，怎么备份？
and like, all my photos and my tax return, and how can I make a backup of that?
但在现代，越来越多的网络应用程序
But increasingly in the modern age, there are more and more web applications
和很多数据只可能存在于一些云服务提供商，比如如果你使用 Webmail，
and a lot of data might only live in some cloud provider, like for example if you have Webmail,
而且你没有将其同步到电脑上，它只存在于提供商的服务器上。
and you're not synchronizing it to your computer, It's only living in that provider's servers
如果你没有这个数据的备份，并且由于某些原因无法访问该帐户，
And if you don't have a copy for that and for some reason you lose access to that account
因为你忘记了密码，被黑客攻击，
because you forgot your password, you got hacked,
他们认为你违反了服务条款...
they think you have violated the terms of service...
所有的数据都会消失。
All that data is gone
因此，你应该寻找一些工具
So you should look into some tools that people have developed
来制作所有这些数据的离线副本，
for making offline copies of all that data
这样你就可以定期备份。
so you can make regular backups of that
这个短小的备份部分就到这里了，
And that kind of ends this short section on backups
有什么问题吗？
Any questions so far?
任何硬盘都可能随时失效，我们没有一个完美的解决方案。
Any drive can fail at any moment. Like we don't...
不同的媒体有不同的故障率，
Different media have different rates of failure
在网上有非常好的统计数据，
and there are really good statistics online
因此，例如，旋转硬盘驱动器的故障率高于SSD，
So for example, spinning hard drives have a higher rate of failure than SSDs for example,
还有固态驱动器
like Solid-State Drives
还有什么情况呢？或者像CD驱动器
And what's another case? Or like CD drives for example
如果你将硬盘掉落，故障率会更高，
But if you drop a hard drive it's a higher rate of that failing, of course
但总体上我们没有一个完美的解决方案。
But in general we don't really have an end-all solution
关于“这个媒体不会失败”的说法，
for saying "this media is not gonna fail
实际上，像SD卡、固态硬盘、硬盘、CD等都会随着时间而逐渐退化，
Like pretty much, like SD cards, SSDs, hard drives, CDs, degrade with time
基本上每种数据都会因此而有可能
Pretty much every data is kind of bound to this degradation
在任何时刻丢失。
or like this fact that it could be lost at any moment
此外，你还需要知道数据也有可能会损坏，
And you should also know that data can become corrupted,
你的硬盘看起来可能没问题，但是有些文件可能已经损坏了，
your disk might look like it's okay, but maybe some files were corrupted
而像Google Drive或Dropbox这样的同步技术
and something like synchronization techniques,
会传播这种损坏。
like Google Drive or Dropbox, will propagate that corruption
等到你意识到出现问题时，可能已经太晚了。
And by the time that you realize that things have gone wrong it's maybe too late
好的，我们将继续跳跃到不同的主题并讨论API。
Alright, we're gonna continue this trend of jumping between random topics and talk about APIs
到目前为止，我们一直在讨论
So so far we've really been talking about
如何在本地计算机上更有效地完成任务。
how do you do things more efficiently locally on your computer?
例如，我想更有效地完成此任务。
Like I want to accomplish this task more efficiently.
我该如何配置我的编辑器？我该如何使用我的shell？
How do I like configure my editor? How do I use my shell?
但你应该意识到，通常你也可以与外界集成。
But one thing you should realize is that very often you can integrate with the outside world as well
你日常互动的大多数服务都提供某种API，
Most services that you interact with in your day-to-day provide some kind of API
供你与其存储的数据或提供的服务进行交互。
For you to interact with the data that they store or the services that they provide
而且通常这些API都有很好的文档。
And usually those APIs are pretty well documented
如果你查看Facebook、Twitter、Google Drive或Gmail等服务的API，
If you looked at the APIs for things like Facebook, or Twitter, or Google Drive, or Gmail
你会发现许多接口都可以供你
Many of these have interfaces that you can interact with
从本地机器上使用这些服务。
in order to use those services from your local machine
真正有趣的是，
What's really neat is that
你通常可以将此与我们迄今为止在课堂上讨论的一些内容相结合。
you can often combine this with some of the stuff that we've talked about in lecture so far
例如，在数据整理的讲座中，
Like for example in the Data Wrangling lecture,
我们介绍了如何创建这些管道
we looked at how you can create  these pipelines to extract data from
以从某些具有不同格式的源中提取数据。
some source that has a different format than you expected
例如，美国政府提供了一个免费服务，
So for instance, the US government has a free service
你可以请求任何美国地点的天气预报。
Where you can request the weather forecast for any given location in the US
你所要做的就是请求一个URL，
And what you do is there is a URL that you request
并在其中设置正确的参数，
And if you set the right parameters in that URL
然后获取数据，你将得到JSON，
and then just fetch it, what you get back is JSON
这是一种定义良好的数据格式，你可以解析它，
Which is sort of a well-defined data format that you can then parse
并提取像未来14天的天气预报之类的信息，
And you can extract things like your 14-day weather forecast
然后你可以将其导入到shell中，
And maybe you then pipe that into your shell
并生成一些方便的别名，以便在终端中打印出
and produce some kind of like Handy alias in your terminal that's just gonna print...
任何位置的
Of some handy reference for the next 14 days of weather
未来14天天气的方便参考。
in whatever location you were in
这些事情你可以相对容易地构建，
These are things you can pretty easily construct and there's some notes...
关于如何构建的说明在笔记中。
There are some notes in the notes about how you might go about this
一般来说，当你与这些API交互时，
In general when you interact with these APIs,
你会使用某种形式的URL，
you're going to be using URLs of one form or another
而确切的格式因服务而异。
And the exact format varies from service to service
但总的来说，URL将包含一些参数集。
But in general the URL is going to contain some set of parameters
最终，你只需向它们发出一个Web请求，
But ultimately you're just gonna issue a web request
然后以某种格式获取数据。
to them and you're gonna get data back in some format
你应该知道的一个命令
One command you should be aware of for interacting with these types of things
是“curl”。
is one called "curl"
所以curl是一个你调用的程序，你给它一个URL。
So curl is a program that you invoke, you give it a URL
它只是获取该URL并把响应返回给你。
And it just fetches that URL and gives you back the response
你对响应做什么，完全取决于你。
What you do with that response is entirely up to you
也许你会通过像“gq”这样的程序进行管道处理。
Maybe you pipe it through a program like "gq".
呸，说错了，是jq
Sorry, "jq"
所以jq是一种JSON查询工具，可以接收JSON格式的数据，
So jq is a JSON query tool that lets you take in data that's formatted as JSON
然后编写查询以提取你感兴趣的数据。
And then write a query over it to extract data that you're interested in
这是你可以使用这些工具
And this is one of the ways in which
提取你感兴趣的数据的一种方式。
you can layer these tools to extract the data that you're interested in
这些服务中的一些还需要你以某种方式进行身份验证。
Some of these services also require that you authenticate in one way or another
例如，如果你想与Facebook API交互，
Like for example if you want to interact with a Facebook API
你需要拥有一些认证令牌，
You need to have some authenticated token that
证明你是Facebook关心的那个人。
proves who you are as far as Facebook is concerned
否则，他们不能说你是否被允许以某个用户身份创建帖子。
Otherwise, they can't say whether you're allowed to say, create a post as a given user
很多时候，这些东西将使用OAuth，虽然并不总是这样。
Very often these things are gonna use something called "OAuth", although not always
你应该查看你关心的每个服务的文档。
And you should look at the documentation for every service you care about
但总的来说，你将从服务中获得一些秘密令牌，
In general though you will get some kind of secret token back from the service
你必须在你发给它们的请求中包含它们。
That you have to include in the requests that you make to them
无论是在URL中还是在附加的Web头中，你也可以通过curl发送它们。
Either in the URL or in additional sort of web headers, which you can also send with curl
但要记住，这些令牌是秘密的。
Keep in mind though that these tokens are secret.
它们是你的用户的另一种表现形式，
They are another representation of your user
任何拿到它们的人都可以假装是你。
And anyone who gets their hand on them can basically pretend to be you
他们可以用那个令牌做你能做的一切。
They can do whatever you can do with that token
所以要记住这一点，不要把它们放在你的“dotfiles”中，
So keep this in mind, don't stick them in your "dotfiles"
然后把它们推到GitHub上。
and then push them onto GitHub
这会让你陷入麻烦。
That will land you in trouble.
你应该把它们当作密码来考虑。
You should think of them as a password
在线上也有一些非常好的工具，可以将服务集成在一起。
There are also really neat tools online for integrating services
有一个叫做“If This Then That”的服务，
So there's a service called "If This Then That"
它基本上提供了对一堆不同的服务的集成，
Which basically provides integrations with a bunch of different services
并允许你将它们链接在一起，
and lets you chain them together
并且如果你愿意，也可以部分地在本地访问它们。
And then also access them partially locally if you wish
这是值得研究的东西。
This is something that's worth looking into
如果你想以更高效的方式与特定服务进行交互，
If there's a particular service you would like to interact with in a more efficient manner
有关API的问题请问？
Any questions about APIs?
好的，我们完全切换话题，
Alright Switching gears entirely,
接下来讨论命令行参数。
let's talk about command-line arguments
命令行工具有很多，大多数都需要不同的参数，
So command-line tools. There are a lot of them
因为它们执行不同的操作。
And most of them take different arguments because they do different things
我们已经谈到过查看命令的man页面，
We've talked about looking at man pages for commands
这会告诉你如何使用这个特定的命令，
and that will tell you how this particular command works
你可以给它什么样的标志和选项，
What kind of flags and options you might give to it
以及当你调用它时它实际执行了什么。
And what it actually does when you invoke it
但是有一些常见的主题是有用的，
But there are some common themes that are useful to know about
无论是许多程序使用的参数，
Either in arguments that many programs take,
还是许多程序都适用的概念。
or just concepts the many of them apply
第一个我们在命令行环境讲座中已经提到了一些，
The first of these we already mentioned a little bit in the lecture on command-line environments
那就是"--help"标志。
Which is the "--help" flag.
通常你可以将这个标志传递给程序，而不是运行它，
Very often you can pass this to a program and instead of running,
它就会打印有关如何运行这个程序的信息，
It will just print out information about
通常是一种非常简短、压缩的方式。
how you can run this program, often in a very short, condensed way
类似的一个是"--version"标志，
A similar one is the "--version" flag,
它只打印你正在使用的软件版本。
which just prints the version of the software you're using
如果你正在进行诸如提交错误报告之类的操作，
This can be really handy if you're doing something like filing a bug report,
（等会Anish会浅浅介绍一下）
Which Anish is going to talk a little bit about later
并且想要报告你正在运行的版本，以防该错误已经修复，那么这非常方便。
And you want to report what version you're running on in case the bug has been fixed since
通常你也可以使用"-V"，它与版本相同。
Often you can also do "-V" and that means the same as version.
但是要检查一下man页面。
But again, check the main page
还有一个经常用到的是"--verbose"或"-v"标志，
There's also "--verbose", or "-v" often
它允许你增加程序的输出，
Which is a flag that lets you increase the output of the program
使程序打印更多有关它正在做什么的信息。
It makes the program print more about what it is doing.
通常你可以重复使用这个标志，
And very often you can repeat this flag
比如使用"-vvvvv"来从该工具获取更多的信息。
So you can do like "-vvvvv" in order to get more information from that tool
如果你正在尝试调试问题，这可能特别有用。
And this can be especially useful if you're trying to debug a problem
如果你正在运行"rsync"，并且想要知道它为什么决定复制这个文件，
If you're like running "rsync" and you want to know why did it decide to copy this file?
或者为什么决定不复制这个文件，
Or why did it decide not to copy this file?
那么这种调试输出就很有用了。
That kind of debug output can be useful
通常还有一个相反的标志叫做"quiet"或"silent"，
And often there's a sort of an inverse flag called "quiet" or "silent"
它意味着工具不会打印任何东西，除非出现错误。
Which means that the tool will not print anything unless it was like an error
很多工具，
Anything else, it will stay quiet about
特别是那些执行破坏性操作
Many tools, especially those that do destructive actions
或你无法撤销的操作，
Or some kind of action that you cannot undo
提供了所谓的"模拟运行标志"。
Provide what's known as a "dry run flag"
这在命令行中的表示方式因工具而异，
Exactly how this is represented in the command line varies from tool to tool
但基本上，这个模拟运行模式会运行该工具，
But essentially what this dry run mode will do is it will run the tool,
但实际上不会进行任何更改，
but it will not actually make any changes
而是只会告诉你
Instead it will just inform you of what it would have done
如果你没有使用模拟运行，它将会做什么。
if you hadn't run it with dry run
许多这些工具也有交互模式。
Many of these tools also have an interactive mode.
例如，“rm”和“mv”工具都有交互模式，
So for example, th "rm" and "mv" tools both do
通常只需要“-i”，但不总是这样。
Often just "-i", although not always
当您在交互模式下运行工具时，
When you run a tool in interactive mode
通常会在即将执行无法撤消的操作时提示您，
It will usually prompt you whenever it's about to do an action that you can't undo
并提示您确认是否应该执行。
And it will sort of prompt you for a confirmation that it should actually go ahead
当我们谈论破坏性工具时，
When we're talking about destructive tools
其中许多默认情况下都不递归。
Many of them are non-recursive by default
如果您尝试删除一个目录或对一个完整的目录进行操作，
If you try to remove a directory or you try to operate on a full directory
则它们不会继续进入该目录内部的文件。
They will not continue into the files inside of that directory
原因是
The reason being you might accidentally like,
您可能会意外地删除整个硬盘，这似乎很糟糕。
remove your entire hard drive and that seems bad
因此，对于许多这些工具，它们都有一个“recurse”标志，
Therefore for many of these tools, they have a "recurse" flag
通常为“-r”，但并非总是如此，
Often "-r", but again not always
它让它们向下遍历树以深入了解，
Which lets them traverse down into the tree to go deeper,
但您需要选择使用此行为。
but you need to opt-in to this behavior
例如，“rm”的情况就是如此，这也是“cp”的情况。
So this is for example, the case for "rm". This is also the case for "cp"
在许多工具中，当它们要求您提供文件名或路径时，
In many tools, when they ask you to give a file name or a path
我们在数据整理讲座中也稍微谈到了这一点，
And we talked about this a little bit in the data wrangling lecture
您通常可以只给出一个破折号“-”，
Instead of giving a file name, you can often just give a dash
这意味着标准输入或标准输出，
Just a single "-", and what that means is standard input or standard output
具体取决于该参数是输入文件还是输出文件。
Depending on whether that argument is an input file or an output file
那么了解这一点非常有用。
This is handy to know about
如果您正在尝试
if you're trying to construct those kinds of
构建我们之前谈到的数据整理流水线，
data wrangling pipelines that we've talked about before
如果您根本不提供任何文件名，
Many tools will also default to using standard in or standard out
许多工具也将默认使用标准输入或标准输出
if you don't give any file name at all
如果您想要传递看起来像是一个标志或选项的东西给一个命令，
Sometimes you want to pass something that looks like a flag or an option to a command
但您实际上不想将其解释为标志或选项，则有时需要考虑一些问题。
But you don't actually want it to be interpreted as a flag or an option
例如，如果您想删除名为“-i”的文件，
Consider for example, if you wanted to remove a file called "-i",
该怎么办？
what would you do?
是的，如果您编写以下命令...
Right, if you write the following command... "rm -i"
“rm -i”，那么“-i”是一个“rm”的标志，因此当您运行此命令时，
Well, "-i" is a flag to "rm", so "rm" would, when you run this command say
“rm”会说“告诉我要删除哪个文件，
Tell me what file to remove, you haven't given me a file
您没有给我一个文件”，因为它将其解释为一个标志。
And it's because it interprets this as a flag
同样，如果您做这样的事情...
Similarly, if you do something like...
“ssh某台机器，某个命令，例如，dash r”，
"ssh some machine, some command, and let's say, dash r"
这就是说-在SSH上运行命令“foo”，
So this is saying - run command "foo" on this machine over SSH,
并且我想向“foo”传递“-r”，
and I wanna pass "-r" to "foo"
那么这两个命令将被解释为标志。
Well, the way that both of these are gonna get interpreted is that these are flags
或者在这个例子中将被解释为标志
Or in this case, this is a flag.
但对于这个命令来说，
But to this command
这可能不是您预期的。
Which is probably not what you expected
实际上，在SSH的情况下，它对某些命令有一些奇怪的特殊行为。
Actually in the case of SSH, it has some weird special behavior for some of these
但是，如果您想要某些东西不被解释为标志，
But often if you want something to not be interpreted as a flag
则有一种非常简单的方法可以选择退出，那就是使用双破折号。
There's a very simple way to opt-out of that, and that is using double dash
如果你使用双破折号，
If you use double dash, what you tell the command is that very thing following this,
那么你告诉命令的是，
you should not interpret
紧跟在其后的内容不应被解释为标志或选项。
So it will not be considered a flag or an option.
在“rm”命令的情况下，你可以这样做，
In the case of "rm" you can do this
现在你会看到第一个参数是“--”，
And now "rm" you will see that the first argument is a "--"
然后它会继续读取参数，但不会将它们解释为标志。
And then it will keep reading arguments, but it will not interpret them as flags
因此，当它遇到“-i”时，它不会将其解释为破折号i标志，
So when it gets the "-i", it will not interpret it as the dash i flag,
而只是作为参数i。
but just as an argument dash i
同样，对于SSH，你也可以这样做，
Similarly, for SSH you can do this
以指示这些都是位置参数，
to indicate that these are both positional arguments
它们不是标志或选项，
They are not flags or options
你不应解释以破折号开头的内容。
and you should not interpret things that start with a dash
(学生)但是，如果你使用“--version”，它不会触发这个吗？
(student) But if you do like "--version", it's not gonna trigger that?
（Jon）不会，这是一个“--”，两侧有空格。
(Jon) No, so this is a " -- ", with a space on both sides
你有任何关于命令行约定的问题吗？
Any questions about any of this sort of command line conventions business?
好的，那么让我们谈谈窗口管理器。
Alright then let's talk about window managers
所以你们大多数人习惯于某种拖放窗口管理器，
So most of you are used to some kind of drag-and-drop window manager
如果你正在运行Windows、Mac OS或Ubuntu，
If you're running Windows, or Mac OS, or Ubuntu -
那么这些机器自带的就是窗口，
what comes with the machine is like, there are windows and
它们在屏幕上部分重叠，
They overlap partially on screen
你可以拖放和移动它们，调整它们的大小等等。
and you can like drag-and-drop and move them around and resize them and stuff
这种方式可以正常工作，
And that works fine
但它并不是管理计算机窗口的唯一方式。
But it is not the only way to manage windows on your computer it turns out
实际上，你习惯的是一种浮动窗口管理器，
So what you are used to is something called a floating window manager,
但并不是所有的窗口管理器都是浮动的。
but not all window managers are floating
通常你可以选择其他类型的窗口管理器，
Often you can opt-in to other types of window managers
它们有不同的行为方式来布置你的桌面。
that have different behavior for how they arrange your desktop
一种常见的替代方案是平铺窗口管理器。
A common alternative is a tiling window manager
在平铺窗口管理器中，不再有浮动窗口，
So in a tiling window manager, rather than having floating windows,
一切都设置成平铺布局。
Everything is set up into a tiled layout.
当你启动一个程序时，它的窗口被最大化。
When you start a program, its window is maximized
如果你启动另一个程序，原来的窗口会缩小，
If you start another program, the original window shrinks in size
新的窗口会占用总桌面空间的一部分。
And then the new window takes up some subset of the total desktop space
除非没有打开任何程序，
At no time is your desktop background visible unless you have no programs open
否则在任何给定的桌面上打开的所有程序
All of the programs you have open on any given desktop
都将共享这个空间。
are going to share that space
这看起来有点像之前我们谈到的tmux面板，
This looks a little bit like tmux panes,
你可以在不同的方向上将它们分割。
like we talked about earlier, where you can sort of split them in various directions
这种方式的一个好处是
And one of the reasons why this is handy
你基本上不需要使用鼠标，
is it means you basically never need to go to your mouse
在不同的窗口之间移动时，
In order to move between windows,
有键盘快捷键可以使用。
there are keyboard shortcuts to move to different windows
有键盘快捷键可以调整窗口的大小
There are keyboard shortcuts for resizing the windows
或在屏幕上交换它们的位置，
or swapping them around on screen
这被证明是一种相当高效的管理计算机窗口的方式。
And this turns out to be a pretty efficient way to manage windows in your computer
我不会详细介绍
Well, I won't go into too much of detail of
你可能会使用哪种窗口管理器，
what kind of window managers you might use
只要知道这些存在并值得一看就好了。
Just know that these exist out there and they're worth giving a look.
它们可以更加高效地工作。
They can be a lot more efficient to work with
关于窗口管理器有什么问题吗？
Questions about window managers?
好的，虚拟私人网络（VPN）。与之前的主题有完全关联。
All right, VPNs. Totally related to the previous topic
所以虚拟私人网络现在非常流行，这让我感到非常难过。
So VPNs are like all the rage these days and this makes me really sad
目前并不清楚使用虚拟私人网络是否有很好的理由。
It's not clear that VPNs are all the rage for any good reason
因为你应该意识到虚拟私人网络能够做什么，以及不能做什么。
Because you should be aware of what a VPN does and does not get you
在最好的情况下，
A VPN, in the best case,
虚拟私人网络只是一种更改你的互联网服务提供商的方法。
is really just a way for you to change your internet service provider
这是一种让互联网上的流量
It's a way for you to make traffic on the Internet
看起来来自于一个比你实际所在的地方更远的地方的方法。
seem like it's coming from somewhere else than where you actually are
虽然这在某些情况下可能看起来很有吸引力，
While that might seem attractive for certain purposes,
但它对于安全性能有什么帮助并不十分明确，
It's a little unclear what it buys you in terms of security
因为你只是转换了你信任的对象。
Because all you're really doing is shifting who you are trusting
你不再信任你当前的互联网服务提供商，
Rather than trusting who is providing your current internet service,
而是信任提供你虚拟私人网络服务的企业……
You're trusting that whatever business is giving you that VPN service...
你首先要相信他们是否已正确设置了这个虚拟私人网络业务，
You're trusting that they, first of all, have set up this VPN business correctly,
还要相信他们不会追踪你正在做什么。
But also that they are not tracking what you are doing
这种信任的改变是否真的值得呢？
And it's not clear whether that change of trust is actually worth it
如果你正在使用一些不安全的公共Wi-Fi网络，那么也许值得考虑。
If you're sitting at some like dodgy public Wi-Fi network then maybe
但如果你在麻省理工学院，
But if you're sitting at MIT,
这并不明显。你是否比信任麻省理工学院的IS&T更信任你的VPN提供商？
it's not clear. Do you trust your VPN provider more than you trust MIT's IS&T?
或许你是这样认为的，但这是你需要考虑的决定，
Or maybe you do, but that is a decision that you need to make about what you trust,
关于你信任什么、信任谁以及为什么？
who you trust and why?
你还应该知道，你的很多流量，
You should also know that much of your traffic,
尤其是敏感性数据在互联网上，
Especially the stuff that's on a sensitive nature on the Internet,
已经被加密了。
is already encrypted
无论是HTTPS还是其他使用类似TLS的协议的数据，
Whether that's sort of HTTPS or other protocols that use something like TLS,
大部分敏感数据都已经通过加密通道发送。
a lot of the sensitive data is already sent over encrypted channels
你的网络提供商是谁并不重要，
and it doesn't really matter who your network provider is
如果你在一个不安全的Wi-Fi网络上，
if you're on a dodgy Wi-Fi network
那些重要的流量可能已经被加密了，
The stuff that matters is probably encrypted anyway.
也可能没有，如果没有，
Might not be, but if it's not
你的VPN提供商也能像
Then your VPN provider can also see it in plain text
托管这个不安全的Wi-Fi网络的人一样看到它的明文。
just as much as whoever's hosting this dodgy Wi-Fi network
请注意，我在上面说的是“在最好的情况下”。
And notice that I said "in the best case above"
有些VPN提供商被证明是恶意的，
There are VPN providers who have been shown to be malicious,
会记录你的所有流量，
that do logging of all your traffic,
将流量出售给第三方。
That sell that traffic to third parties.
有些VPN提供商忘记在VPN上启用加密，
There are VPN providers that have forgotten to enable encryption on the VPN
所有这些都是真实存在的问题。
All of these are real problems
因此，您应该非常仔细地考虑VPN
And so you should think very carefully about whether a VPN
是否真正为您提供了任何好处。
actually serves any good purpose for you
有关VPN的问题？是的？
Questions about VPNs? Yes?
（学生）所以我有一个关于公共Wi-Fi网络的问题，
(student) So I have a question about public Wi-Fi networks, because
因为电脑和路由器之间的流量
The traffic from your computer to the router isn't encrypted
在计算机和路由器之间没有加密，对吧？
between the computer and the router, right?
除了通常通过HTTPS
Except for what normally is via HTTPS and
和[不可理解的]那么这是否意味着人们可以通过DNS请求嗅探出
[unintelligible] So then doesn't that mean that people could sniff out what domains
我正在访问哪些域名？
I'm going to via the DNS request?
(Jon)这是一个非常好的问题。
(Jon) So, it's a very good question
如果您在公共Wi-Fi网络上，
If you're on a public Wi-Fi network,
则您与无线接入点之间的流量没有加密。
then the traffic between you and the wireless access point is not encrypted
至少在外层上没有加密，
At least it's not encrypted sort of on the outer layer,
但它可能在像HTTPS这样的加密层中加密。
but it might be encrypted in like HTTPS, for example
这是完全正确的，
And it is totally true the people observing that
观察Wi-Fi网络的人将能够看到未加密的任何内容。
Wi-Fi network will be able to see anything that is not encrypted
但解决方法是加密所有流量，
But the solution to that is to encrypt all your traffic,
而不一定要通过VPN。
rather than necessarily going through a VPN
例如，可以使用DNS over TLS
So one way to do this for example is to use DNS over TLS
或DNS over HTTPS的方式来实现这一点，
or DNS over HTTPS, which gives you a way to actually encrypt even information
这可以使本来可能以明文泄露的信息得到加密。
that might otherwise leak in plain text
而不是试图相信某个提供商为您做到这一点。
Rather than try to sort of trust some provider to do that for you
当然，在某些情况下，
Now that said,  in some cases
您可能有一个可信赖的机构为您提供VPN网络。
you might have a trusted institution that provides a VPN network for you
例如，MIT为所有MIT学生和工作人员提供VPN网络，
So for example, MIT provides a VPN network for all MIT students and staff
您可以注册使用。
that you can sign up to use
在这种情况下，您可能更信任MIT而不是其他可能连接的网络。
And in that case you probably trust MIT more than the other networks you might be on
所以这可能值得一试，但这是您需要考虑的事情。
So it might be worth it, but it's something for you to think about
(学生)当你说你可以用DNS加密它，是什么意思？
(student) When you say you could encrypt it with, what was it, DNS, how would you do that?
(Jon)DNS是人们将域名转换成IP地址的方式，
(Jon) So, DNS is the way that people turn domain names,
或者说是您的计算机将域名转换成IP地址
Or your computer turns domain names into IP addresses
以了解要连接到哪台计算机的协议。
to know what computer to connect to
默认情况下，该协议是明文的，
And that protocol by default is in plain text.
没有任何加密。
There's nothing encrypted about it
有各种各样的方法可以加密DNS流量。
There are various ways to encrypt your DNS traffic
其中一些是标准化的，而一些不是。
Some of them are standardized and some of them are not
我不会在这里详细介绍机制，
I won't go into the exact mechanics here,
但您应该搜索一下并查看一些方法。
but you should google it and look at some of the ways
好的，我想谈论的最后一件事是Markdown。
Okay. The last thing I want to talk about is Markdown
因此，很有可能你们中的一些人
So there is a high chance that some of you are going to write text
会在余生中写文本，
over the remaining part of your life
并且你们会想以各种简单的方式标记这些文本。
And you will want to mark up that text in various simple ways
你可以启动Word或使用LaTeX等
And one thing you could do is start up Word or use LaTeX or something like that
来标记你的文档，
to mark up your documents
但这是一种相当笨重的方法。
But that is a pretty heavy-handed approach
相反，如果我们能够以
Instead it would be nice if we could just sort of
自然的方式写东西，那将是很好的。
Write things the way we feel like they should be
我不知道如何更好地描述它，但是它是自然的方式，
I don't know how to describe it in a better way but sort of the natural way
如果你想强调一个词，
where if you want something,
你只需要在它周围放上星号或其他东西，
If you want to put emphasis on a word you just put like stars around it or something,
然后它就起作用了。
and then it just works
Markdown本质上就是这样。
Markdown is essentially that. It is a way to try to encode the way
它是一种尝试将我们通常自然地编写文本的方式
that we often write text somewhat naturally
编码到一种标记语言中，使您可以编写粗体文本、链接、列表等等。
Into a markup language that lets you write things like bold text, links, lists, that sort of stuff
事实上，本课程的所有讲义都是使用Markdown编写的。
In fact, all of the lecture notes for this class have been written using Markdown
Markdown非常简单明了，
And Markdown is really very straightforward.
基本规则在讲义中，
The basic rules are in the notes
但您需要知道的基本事项是，在Markdown中，如果您在一个词的周围放上星号，
But the basic things you need to know is, in Markdown if you put stars
那么这个词就被强调了。
Around a word, that word is emphasized.
或者是一些词序列。
Or some sequence of words.
如果您在一个词的周围放上双星号，
If you put double stars
那么这个词就会被强调为加粗。
That word is emphasized strongly, also known as bold
您还可以做各种其他的事情，
There are various other things you could do,
例如如果你在一行前加上破折号，那么这一行就成为一个列表了。
like if you put a dash before a line it is now a list
然后你就可以添加列表项了。
And there's one list item and you can amend list items
如果在列表项前加上“1.”或其他数字，它就成为了一个有序列表。
If you put "1." in front, or some other number, it becomes a numbered list
如果在内容前面加上井号，
If you put a pound sign in front of something
它就会变成标题，就像是某种标题。
it becomes a header, like some kind of title header
如果加多个井号，它们就变成了子标题，
If you put multiple of them, they become subheadings
你可以继续添加更多。
and you can keep adding more to these
如果你想编写代码，
If you want to write code you can put a single backtick,
可以在单引号之间输入代码，
followed by some code, followed by a backtick
然后它将以等宽字体呈现。
And now that is rendered in Monospaced Font
如果要多行代码，可以使用三个反引号，
If you want multiple lines of code, you do a triple backtick, and then code,
然后是代码和更多的代码，最后再使用三个反引号。
And then maybe some more code and then triple backtick
在许多情况下，如果你在GitHub上，
And in many cases like if you're on GitHub for example,
你甚至可以在反引号之后输入一个语言名称，而不需要空格，
You can even type the name of a language up here after the backticks,  without a space
它会以你选择的语言进行语法高亮显示。
And it will be syntax highlighted in the language of your choice
这是一件非常方便的事情，
This is a really handy thing
在如此多的网站上都支持它，你甚至可能没有意识到。
that is supported in so many websites nowadays you might not even realize
就像在Facebook Messenger中，你可以使用许多这样的功能。
Like in Facebook Messenger you can use many of these
它们没有正式说明它们在任何地方都支持Markdown，
They don't actually officially say they support Markdown anywhere
但许多这样的事情只是发生了，
But many of these things just like sort of happen to work
值得学习至少基础知识并开始使用它们。
and it's worth learning at least the basics and just start using them.
你也可以创建链接，但这已经在笔记中提到了。
You can do links and stuff as well, but that's already in the notes
有关Markdown的问题吗？好的，Anish，轮到你了。
Any questions about Markdown? Right, Anish, you're up
（Anish）我的麦克风工作吗？这个工作吗？你们能在后面听到我吗？
(Anish) Is my microphone working? Is this working? Can you guys hear me in the back?
灯亮了。哦，我想我能听到。
The light's green. Oh, I think I can hear it. Okay, great
好的，继续我们随机话题的主题，
So, continuing with our theme of random topics
这些主题与我们之前讨论的主题都没有关系。
that are all unrelated to the previous topics we've been talking about,
接下来我们要讨论的是
The next thing we're going to talk about
一个叫做“Hammerspoon”的程序，
is a program called "Hammerspoon"
它是Mac OS上进行桌面自动化的工具，
Which is a tool for doing desktop automation on Mac OS
我认为Windows和Linux也有类似的工具，很多想法可以继承下来。
And I think there's similar tools for Windows and Linux, a lot of the ideas can carry over
如果你想知道如何在其他平台上实现这些功能，可以谷歌一下。
You can google it if you want to figure out how to do these things on other platforms
基本上，Hammerspoon是一个程序，它让你编写用Lua编写的脚本，
But basically Hammerspoon is a program that lets you write Lua scripts,
这些脚本
scripts in a programming language
与各种操作系统功能进行交互。
that interact with various operating system functionality
因此，你可以编写代码来与键盘和鼠标交互，
So you can write code that interacts with the keyboard and mouse
并将其连接到窗口管理、
and connects that to window management,
显示管理、文件系统、电池和电源管理、Wi-Fi等等。
to display management, the file system, battery and power management, Wi-Fi...
基本上，
All sorts of stuff
所有操作系统管理的东西，
Like basically all the things that your operating system manages,
这个工具都可以让你钩入这些东西。
this tool lets you hook into those things
因此，你可以通过编写几行代码做所有的很酷的事情。
And so it can let you do all sorts of neat things by writing just a couple lines of code
这个工具可以做的一些很酷的事情的例子是：
Just some examples of cool things you can do with this tool are -
你可以绑定热键来移动窗口。
you can bind hotkeys to move windows to specific locations.
这里有一个演示。我把这个窗口打开。
So a demonstration of this is here. I have this window open.
我按下，按照我的特定设置，
I press, in my particular setup,
"Option+Command+Right"，这个窗口就会向右移动。
"Option+Command+Right" and this window moves to the right.
"Option+Command+Left"，这个窗口就会向左移动。
"Option+Command+Left", this window moves to the left
我还有一些其他的快捷键可以将窗口移动到不同的位置。
And I have a couple other shortcuts for moving things to various places
这样我就可以达到类似于
And so I can kind of have an effect similar to
Jon之前谈到的平铺窗口管理器的效果，
tiling window managers that Jon was talking about earlier
将窗口移动到屏幕的不同部分，以特定的方式设置东西，
I can move windows to different parts of my screen to set things up in a particular way
而不必使用鼠标将东西放在我想要的位置，
rather than have to use the mouse to position things where I want them to be
然后点击和拖动来调整窗口的大小。
and then like click and drag to resize windows to the right shape
只需要一个键盘快捷键就可以搞定。
Just a keyboard shortcut can do the trick
但是这个工具不仅限于仅仅移动窗口
But this tool is not limited to just moving windows around
并将其绑定到特定的键盘快捷键上。
and binding that to particularly keyboard shortcuts
你还可以做其他的事情，比如创建一个菜单栏按钮，里面有很多不同的选项，
You can do other things like create a menu bar button with a bunch of different options
你可以将这些不同的选项绑定到不同的操作。
And you can bind those different options to do different things.
所以在我的特定情况下，我创建了这个小菜单，
So in my particular case I've created this little menu
然后我有很多不同的事情，我相当频繁地做这些事情，
and then I have a bunch of different things that I do reasonably frequently
点击这些事情
and clicking on these things
会调用我编写的一个特定的Lua函数，与这个库进行交互。
Invokes a particular Lua function that I've written that interacts with this library.
例如，
So for example
这个“Rescue windows”是
Here, this "Rescue windows" thing
一个我经常使用多个显示器的特定问题，
is a particular thing where I often work with multiple displays
有时我的操作系统会混淆，
And sometimes my operating system gets confused
我有一些窗口出现在我的显示器之外，
and I have some window that ends up off of my display and
我该如何将这个东西拿回来呢？
How do I how do I get this thing back?
emmmmmm
Well, that's what this... Whoops, not that
那就是这个“Rescue windows”所做的事情。
That's what this "Rescue windows" thing does.
它将那些超出屏幕的窗口重新放回屏幕上。
It brings windows that are off the screen back onto the screen
我在这里设置的另一个很酷的东西是我有特定的布局，我已经命名了它们。
Another neat thing I have setup here is I have particular layouts that I've named
比如一个宿舍、一个实验室和一个笔记本电脑布局。
So like a dorm, and a Lab and a Laptop layout
所以在我的实验室里，我有这个屏幕
So for example in my Lab I have this screen and I have another screen
和另一个屏幕和另一个屏幕，方向不同。
and have another screen besides that in a different orientation
我有这个特定的设置，
And I have this particular setup that I want where I want
我想在这里可能我的终端全屏显示，在这里显示我的聊天程序，
Maybe my terminal full screen on here, and my chat program over here and
这个屏幕分成五个不同的部分，有不同的程序放在不同的地方。
This screen split up into five segments with different programs in different places
在我到实验室的时候，我可以点击“布局实验室”，
Here I can, when I show up to Lab I can just go here and click "Layout Lab"
它将调用一些代码，
and it will invoke some code
描述了一个特定的布局，这并不是很复杂，只有10行代码，
Which is not all that complicated like 10 lines of code describes a particular layout
它会实例化这个布局，并把所有东西放到需要放的地方。
And it will instantiate that layout and put all the things where they need to go
我甚至可以在理论上自动化其中的一些过程，
I could even in theory automate some of these things
让我的电脑可以自己识别，比如我插上一个显示器，我的电脑就知道：
where my computer could figure out like I plug in a display and my computer knows
“哦，这是你实验室里的显示器。
Oh, this is the display that you have in your lab.
让我自动创建这个布局给你。
Let me automatically instantiate this layout for you
这是使用 Hammerspoon 工具的另一种方法。
That's another thing you can do with Hammerspoon.
还有其他一些有趣的事情，
And also other wacky things you can do like you can do things like
比如可以检测您所在的 Wi-Fi 网络，
It can detect your Wi-Fi network that you're on
这样就可以知道您所在的位置。
so it knows kind of where you are
也许我在家里和在实验室的 Wi-Fi 网络名称不同，
Maybe I have a different Wi-Fi network name at home versus in lab
那么我可以做一些事情，比如当我到实验室时
and I can do things like when I show up to lab
自动将扬声器静音，
Automatically mute my speakers.
这样我就不会在实验室里尴尬地播放音乐了。
So I don't have like embarrassing music play out loud in my lab
另一个很酷的例子是，
Another kind of cool example is
我有一台 Mac 电脑，它有一个高级电源适配器，
So I have a Mac It has a fancy power supply
我的很多朋友的电脑看起来都和我的一样，
and a lot of my friends have Computers that look the same as this
他们的电源适配器看起来也和我的一样，
and their power supply bricks look the same as mine
有时候我会用他们的电源适配器，因为我把我的忘在家里了或者其他原因。
Sometimes I use their power brick because I forgot mine at home or something
这个工具实际上可以使用三到四行代码做一些好玩的事情，
This tool can actually with like three or four lines of code
比如弹出一个警告，
Do neat things like show you a warning like it'll pop up a warning
当你意外拿了朋友的电源适配器并插到电脑上时，
if you've accidentally taken your friend's power supply and plugged it Into your computer
而非你自己的
instead of using your own
所以，从高层次上讲，这个工具允许您运行任意 Lua 代码，
So at a high level this tool lets you run arbitrary Lua code
并将其绑定到菜单按钮或按键上，
and do things like bind it to menu buttons or key presses
它与操作系统的大部分交互，以执行各种有趣的事情。
It interacts with a large part of the operating system in order to do all sorts of cool stuff
这就是 Hammerspoon，对此还有什么问题吗？
So that is Hammerspoon, any questions about that?
好的，接下来讲另一个话题，
Cool. Moving on to the next topic
和之前没有任何关系，就是启动和使用 Live USB。
Completely unrelated to the previous one, it's booting and live USBs
您的计算机上的操作系统，比如 Windows 或 Mac OS 或其他您习惯的操作系统，
So the operating system on your computer, Windows or Mac OS or whatever you're used to
实际上不是在开机时第一件运行的东西。
is not exactly the first thing that runs on your machine when it turns on.
在操作系统加载之前，
There's something else that happens in the boot process
启动过程中会发生其他一些事情。
before your operating system is loaded
有些有趣的东西可以在这里配置。
and There's some interesting stuff that you can do there.
您可能已经看到，当您打开计算机时，
So you might have seen when you turn on your computer
它会显示类似“按 F9 键配置 BIOS”
It says something like press F9 to configure the BIOS
或“按 F12 进入启动菜单”的消息。
or press F12 to enter the boot menu
特定的按键序列可能会因
The particular key sequences may depend on your machine
您的机器和具体配置而有所不同，
and specific configuration But this is a general pattern
但这是一个通用的模式，您可以在这里配置各种有趣的硬件相关的内容。
and you can configure all sorts of interesting Hardware related stuff here
因此，这值得一试。
So it's worth checking out
在这个启动菜单中，
And another thing you can do in this boot menu is you can
您可以让计算机从备用启动设备开始启动。
have your computer start off from an alternate boot device
例如，默认情况下，我的笔记本有一个固态硬盘，当它开机时会启动 Mac OS，
so by default like my laptop here has a solid-state drive and it boots Mac OS when it turns on
但是我也可以插入
but I can also say plug in a USB flash drive
一个安装有操作系统的 USB 闪存驱动器，
that has an operating system installed on the flash drive
然后在开机时告诉计算机从那个闪存驱动器
and then at boot tell my computer to boot from that flash drive
而不是内置的固态硬盘开始启动。
instead of the built-in solid-state disk,
这对于例如我破坏了操作系统安装，
and this is useful for example If I've broken my operating system install
需要做一些事情，比如获取计算机上的数据，
and I want to do something like get the data off my computer
或者修复操作系统。
or maybe want to fix the operating system
比如可能有些关键文件被删除了，
Like maybe there's some critical files somewhere that I've deleted
或者我忘记了密码，
or I forgot my password I need to go like tweak some files in order to reset it
需要去调整一些文件以重置它。
booting from a live USB
从一个Live USB启动计算机，从安装在闪存驱动器上的独立操作系统引导，
Booting from the separate operating system that's installed on a flash drive
可以让我做到这一点，就像启动我的操作系统，
can let me do that like boot up my operating system
挂载在我当前机器上的硬盘一样。
Mount the hard disk that's on my current machine I'm working on
我正在处理的任务,然后进行一些调整或者将数据复制出来。
and then go make some tweaks or copy data off of that
因此，live USB非常有用，在课堂笔记中，
And so live USBs are really useful and in the lecture notes,
我们提供了一个工具，可以帮助您轻松创建live USB。
we've linked to a tool that can help you create them really easily
有关启动过程或live USB的任何问题吗？
Any questions about the boot process or live USBs?
好的，下一个话题是虚拟机、Vagrant、Docker、云和OpenStack。
All right, next topic is virtual machines, Vagrant, Docker, the cloud and OpenStack
去年我们整整开了一个讲座来探讨这个话题，
I think last year we had an entire lecture on this topic
今年我们将把它压缩到一分钟内。
this year We're going to condense it into like one minute
在高层次上，虚拟机和类似的工具，如容器，
So at a high level virtual machines and similar tools like containers
可以让您在当前计算机系统内模拟整个计算机系统，
let you emulate a whole computer system within your current machine
例如，我正在运行Mac OS，
so like I'm running Mac OS here,
但在我的Mac OS环境内，
but within my Mac OS environment I can simulate a machine
我可以模拟运行Ubuntu或其他操作系统的机器。
that's running say Ubuntu or some other operating system
这是创建用于测试、
And this is a nice way of creating an isolated environment
开发或探索的隔离环境的好方法，
for testing or for development or for exploration
例如运行潜在的恶意代码
For example doing things like running potentially malicious code
应该与我的当前环境隔离。
that should be isolated from my current environment.
我认为程序员最常见的用例是
I think the most common use case for programmers is to use
使用虚拟机或容器创建开发环境。
virtual machines are containers to create development environments
我使用Mac OS，并在我的当前计算机上
So I'm using Mac OS and I have some of services and stuff
安装了一些服务、库等，
and libraries installed in my current machine
但我可能想要在Debian机器上运行某些Web编程项目，
But I might want for example I'm working on some web programming project
并需要安装Postgres等数据库服务器，
and I want it to run on an Debian machine and I need Postgres,
而不是在我的Mac OS机器上安装所有这些。
like a database server installed rather than install that all on my Mac OS machine
我可以为开发目的实例化这个新机器。
I can instantiate this new machine just for the development purposes
虚拟机是一个普遍的概念。
Now virtual machines, like that's a general concept.
有许多程序可以被称为
There are a bunch of programs that let you
虚拟机超级监视程序，
that are called virtual machine hypervisors that
支持您在计算机上实现这个功能。
support this functionality on your machine
还有一些工具，让您可以脚本化这些超级监视程序，
and then there are tools that let you script these hypervisors
以便指定机器配置，
in order to specify machine configurations like
如操作系统，您想要安装哪些软件包
operating system and like what packages you want installed
以及您想要安装哪些服务。
and what services you want installed in plain text
这是屏幕上的一个示例。
And so this is an example on the screen right here.
这是使用名为Vagrant的系统完成的。
And this is done using a system called Vagrant.
在课程笔记中有链接，如果您感兴趣可以了解一下。
It's linked in the lecture notes. You can look into this if you're curious.
因此，在简短的纯文本文件中，
So basically and the short plain text file I can specify
我可以指定一个正在运行Debian的机器，
okay. I want a machine that's running Debian
它应该安装了Postgres、Redis和Python等软件。
It should have "postgres" and Redis and Python and stuff installed on it.
然后，一旦我有了这个配置，
And then, once I have this configuration,
我只需要输入"vagrant up"，
I can just type in "vagrant up",  and what it does is,
它会读取这个文件并根据这个配置实例化一个新的虚拟机。
it reads this file and instantiates a new machine based on this configuration.
然后，在我这样做后，我可以通过"vagrant ssh"来SSH进入这个虚拟机。
And then, after I've done that I can do "vagrant ssh" to SSH into this virtual machine.
所以它不是在其他硬件上运行的远程机器，
So it's not a remote machine running on some other piece of hardware somewhere,
它只是在我的机器上模拟，
It's just simulated on my own machine,
但现在我在这里有一个像我现在拥有的Ubuntu盒子一样的盒子，
but now here I have an Ubuntu box like I do now, let's be really stashe
这里没有一堆的debian
It's like or sorry not a bunch of debian here
和我想要安装的所有东西，
with all the things I want installed in here
我可以在这个隔离的环境中进行开发，
and I can do my development inside this isolated environment,
而不是在我的MacOS机器上安装所有这些垃圾。
and not, kind of, install all this junk on my MacOS machine.
现在有类似的工具，如Docker，
Now so that's vagrant there's similar tools like docker
它们在概念上类似，但是使用容器而不是虚拟机。
that are conceptually similar but use containers instead of virtual machines
这是一个区别，我们现在不会详细讨论。
It's a distinction that we're not going to talk about in too much detail right now
因此，你可以在自己的计算机上运行虚拟机，
And so you can run VMs on your own computer
但你也可以在云上租用虚拟机，
but you can also rent virtual machines on the cloud
这是一个很好的
and so It's a nice way to get instant access to
获得即时访问的方式，
like one example is you might want a computer
比如你可能想要一个始终开着、始终连接到互联网并具有公共IP地址的计算机。
That's always on always connected to the internet and has a public IP address.
比如你想运行一个始终可用的Web服务器，
Like maybe you want to run a web server
或者你想运行一些其他的服务，
That's always available or you want to run some other service like
比如一个slack机器人之类的东西。
say a slack bot or something like that
在云上租用虚拟机是一个不错的选择，
Well a virtual machine rented on the cloud is one nice way to get that
这些虚拟机对于低容量的机器
and these are pretty cheap for like a low capacity machine
和小型CPU和少量的磁盘空间来说都是很便宜的。
with a small CP and small amount of disk space
你可能想做的是获得一个非常强大的机器，
and you might want to do is get access to a machine
比如有很多CPU核心或者有很多内存或者有大量的GPU，
that's really powerful like with a lot of CPU cores  or with a lot  of RAM
用于某些特定的目的，
or with a whole bunch of GPUs for some specific purpose like
比如说你正在进行深度学习
say you're doing deep learning
或者其他一些敏感的计算。
or so you're doing some other sorts of sensitive computation
那么，这也是使用云上的虚拟机可以做的事情。
Well, that's another thing you can do with VMs on the cloud
最后，你可以获得比你实际可以访问的机器更多的机器。
And finally, you can get access to many more machines than you have physical access to.
比如，如果我需要一千台机器，
Like if I need a thousand machines
但只需要两分钟来完成一些非常并行的任务，
But only for two minutes to do some very parallel tasks.
那么我可以很容易地使用虚拟机来完成。
That's something I can easily do with virtual machines
用于执行此操作的流行服务包括Amazon AWS或Google Cloud。
Popular services for doing this are things like Amazon AWS or Google cloud
如果你是MIT CSAIL的成员，你也可以使用CSAIL OpenStack
And if you're a member of MIT CSAIL, you can also get free VMs
获得免费的虚拟机进行研究。
for research purposes using the CSAIL OpenStack
这个在课堂笔记中有链接
And so this is also linked in the lecture notes
所以，关于虚拟机、Vagrant、Docker或其他类似的东西，有任何问题吗？
So any questions about virtual machines, or Vagrant, Docker, or anything like that?
问题是当我说我在运行Ubuntu时，实际上在这种情况下，我运行的是Debian，
So the question is when I say I'm running Ubuntu, or, actually, in this case, it's Debian
那么我是否像运行Ubuntu一样在我的电脑上安装了Ubuntu，
when I'm running Ubuntu here, do I have, like, Ubuntu installed on my machine,
还是发生了什么情况？
or What exactly is going on here?
基本上，当我键入“vagrant up”时，Vagrant为我做的是，
So, basically, what Vagrant did for me when I type "vagrant up" is,
因为我指定我想要Debian，
because I've specified I want Debian here,
它从互联网上下载了Debian，
it downloaded Debian from the internet,
为这台新机器设置了一个磁盘映像，
like, set up a disk image for this new machine,
将Debian安装到该磁盘映像中，然后安装了这些程序。
installed Debian into that disk image, then went to install these programs
所以，是的，这在我的电脑上。
So, like, yes, this is on my computer.
但是，所有这些都只是在一个特定的文件中，这是一个磁盘映像。
But, all of this is just in a particular file that's a disk image.
然后，我正在模拟一台与我的电脑完全隔离的机器。
And then, I'm emulating a machine that is basically completely isolated from my current machine.
这是在我的电脑上作为一个进程运行的。
This is being run as a process on my current machine.
这回答了你的问题吗？还有其他关于虚拟机的问题吗？
Does that answer the question? Any other questions about VMs?
好的，下一个话题也会是一个简短的提及。
Great. Next topic is also going to be a quick mention -
很多人是程序员，你们习惯使用像Vim这样的工具编写程序，
So, a lot of you are programmers, and you're used to writing programs
或者使用其他你们熟悉的编辑器。
in a tool like Vim, or some other editor that you're comfortable with.
但是，另一件非常实用的东西是，
Another thing that can be really neat to use for particular tasks,
可以为特定任务使用笔记本编程环境。
is something called a notebook programming environment.
这是一种更加交互式的编程方式。
And this is a more interactive way of writing programs.
在屏幕上，我有一个演示。
Here on the screen, I have a demo.
这是一个叫做Jupyter笔记本，
This is something called Jupiter notebook
它可以用于编写Python程序。
and it can be used for writing Python programs.
我认为它们也支持其他一些语言。
I think they also support some other languages.
基本上，这是一个很好的交互式编程方式。
And, basically, this is a nice way of doing interactive programming.
通常，你们习惯在一个文件或一组文件中编写一个大程序，
So, normally, you're used to writing a big program in a file, or a collection of files,
一旦完成，就可以运行整个程序。
and once you're done writing it, you can just run the whole program.
但是，这让你更加灵活，并逐段运行代码。
But, this lets you be a little bit more flexible and run little snippets of code at a time.
例如，我可以将我的程序分成这些小段，
Like, for example, I can break my program into these little pieces.
这只是我写的一些随机代码。
It's just some random code I wrote.
然后，我可以说，“执行这个单元格”，
And, I can say, "execute this cell",
然后按下特定的组合键来执行该单元格。
and I press a particular key combination to execute the cell.
但是，我可以回去稍微修改我的程序，
But then, I can go back, and tweak my program a little bit.
例如，我想要将它变成小写。
Like, say I want to have this be lowercase instead.
然后，我可以执行这个单元格，然后去评估这个东西，
Then, I can execute this cell, and then go and evaluate this thing,
这样我就可以在Python环境中运行一些小段的代码。
and this way I can, kind of, run little snippets of code, within a Python environment.
这是一个很好的逐步构建程序的方式，
And, it's a nice way of building up programs, piece by piece,
而不是一次性编写所有代码。
rather than having to write everything at once.
这对特定的研究目的非常有用，
This is really useful for particular research purposes,
例如，我认为很多人用它来进行机器学习工作。
like I think a lot of people use these for doing machine learning work, for example.
对于笔记本编程环境的概念有任何问题吗？
Any questions about the idea of notebook programming environments?
这里有很多问题值得一问
They're worth checking out.
哦，问题是，
Oh, so the question is,
“这看起来像是在线的，有没有Jupyter笔记本的离线版本？”
"This looks like it's online, is there an offline version of Jupiter notebooks?"
实际上，这是在浏览器中运行的东西，但它是本地运行的……
So, actually, this is the thing that runs in the browser, but it's running locally...
所以，我不知道你能否在屏幕上看到，因为它有点小，
So, I don't know if you can see it on the screen, because it's kind of small,
但在这里，
but up here it says, "localhost:8888".
我在自己的本地机器上运行一个Jupyter笔记本。
Here, I have running on my own local machine, a Jupiter notebook.
他们只是建立了它，让它在Web浏览器中运行。
And, they've just built it so it runs within the web browser.
话虽如此，
That being said, there are also online
也有在线Jupyter笔记本可供使用，
Jupiter notebooks that you can use,
其中Python内核实际上在一些远程机器上运行。
where the Python kernel is actually running on some remote machine.
你可能会想这样做，例如，在我的笔记本电脑上，
You might want to do this for example, like on my laptop,
我没有一个高级的GPU，但在我的房间里，我有一台装有高级GPU的机器。
I don't have a fancy GPU, but in my room,I have a machine with a fancy GPU.
所以，当我做机器学习的工作时，
And so, when I'm doing machine learning  work,
我经常通过SSH登录到那台机器，运行Jupiter笔记本，
I often SSH into that machine, run a Jupiter notebook on there,
然后在本地的Web浏览器中打开界面，
and then open up the interface, in my local web browser,
以便访问那台运行在另一台机器上的强大GPU。
so I have access to that powerful GPU running on my different machine.
还有其他问题吗？
Any other questions?
好的。今天我们要讨论的最后一件事是Github。
Great. The final thing we're going to talk about today is Github.
我们在版本控制讲座中已经提到了一点。
So, we touched on this a little bit during the version control lecture.
但是，Github是最受欢迎的开源软件开发平台之一。
But, Github is one of the most popular platforms for open-source software development.
它托管源代码
It hosts source code.
和git存储库。
It hosts git repositories.
但是，他们还有其他工具来管理项目。
But, they also have other tools for managing a project.
而且，像我们在这门课程中谈论过的许多工具一样，都托管在Github上。
And, like, a lot of the tools we've talked about in this class are hosted on Github.
例如，像我们刚刚谈论的Hammerspoon就是在Github上开发的。
For example, like, Hammerspoon, the thing we just talked about, is developed on Github
在Github上开始为开源项目做贡献
It's really easy to get started  contributing to open-source projects on Github
以帮助改进您每天使用的工具非常容易。
to help improve the tools that you use every day.
您可以通过两种主要方式为Github上的项目做出贡献。
There are two primary ways you can contribute to projects on Github.
让我们打开一些存储库。
Let's open up some repository.
我们实际上可以进入课程网站的Github存储库。
We can actually go to the Github repository for the class website.
这是一个开源软件项目。
So, this is an open-source software project.
让我们放大一点。
And... Let's zoom in a little bit.
因此，您可以通过问题和拉取请求这两种主要方式
So the two ways you can contribute to projects on Github -
为Github上的项目做出贡献。
The two main ways are through issues and pull requests
实际上，对于开发人员来说，这是一件非常有用的事情，
One thing that's actually really helpful to developers,
对用户来说也相对轻松和简单，就是报告软件项目的问题。
and also pretty lightweight and easy for users to do, is to report issues with a software project.
比如说，您正在使用某个程序，遇到了一些错误...
Like, say you're using somebody's program and you encounter some bug...
编写高质量的问题对开发人员非常有帮助，
Writing a high quality issue is actually super helpful to developers
希望不会花费太多时间。
and hopefully doesn't take you too much time.
因此，您可以前往Github上找到项目，进入问题页面，
And so, you can go to here, like find the project on GitHub, go to the issues page,
然后单击新问题，并编写一些高质量的错误报告。
and click on new issue, and then write some high quality bug report.
然后，希望开发人员会回复并为您修复问题。
And then, hopefully the developer will respond and fix the issue for you.
例如，在这门课程中，
So, for example, for this class,
一个学生指出了我们的讲座笔记中的问题，
like, one of the students in this class pointed out an issue with our lecture notes,
当她指出后
and after she pointed it out,
我说，好的，看起来是一个合理的问题。让我们来解决它。
I said, okay, like, that looks like a reasonable thing. Let's fix it.
在这种情况下，
And in this particular case, instead of fixing it myself,
我实际上询问了这个人，“他们想不想为我解决问题？”
I actually asked this person, "Do they just want to fix it for me?"
因此，我想谈论另一件事：问题和拉取请求。
And so, that leads into the other thing I want to talk about: issues and pull requests.
拉取请求是在Github上为项目做出贡献的第二种方法。
So, pull requests are the second way to contribute to projects on Github.
这涉及实际向项目贡献代码。
And, this involves actually contributing code back to the project.
如果我们查看此项目的拉取请求，
And so if we look at the pull request for this particular project,
您会看到许多人提交了代码更改。
you'll see that a bunch of people have submitted code changes.
而且，这样做的过程 -
And, the process for doing so - so this is showing the difference, the patch,
所以这显示了这个人提交的区别，补丁。
that this person submitted.
基本上，创建拉取请求的过程比提交问题要复杂一些。
Basically, the process for creating pull requests is a little bit more involved than submitting issues.
您不只是提交文本：您实际上要修改他们的源代码。
Like you're not just submitting text: you're actually going to modify their source code.
我们提供了一些解释该过程的指南链接。
And so, we've linked to some guides that explain the process in a little bit more detail.
但总体来说，您需要在Github上“分叉”存储库，
But, at a high level, what you do is, you take the repository on Github,
然后将其下载到本地，这样就有了自己的本地副本。
"fork" it, and then download it locally, so now have your own, local copy.
然后，您可以开始工作，进行一些开发工作，
Then, you can go and work on it, do some development work,
修复错误或添加功能，
and fix a bug or add a feature, and then, eventually,
最终将所做的更改发送回原始开发人员，称为“拉取请求”。
you send what's called a "pull request" back to the original developer.
所以，你说，'在这里。我做了一些更改。
So, you say, 'Here. I've made some changes.
你能把它们重新纳入原始项目中吗？
Can you please incorporate them back into the original project?'
然后，通常情况下，
And, after that point, what usually happens with these projects,
项目维护者将与您交流，
is that the maintainer will go back and forth with you,
对您所提出的更改进行反馈。
giving you feedback on the changes you've proposed.
最终，一旦大家都满意，他们会合并您的更改，
And, eventually, once everybody's happy, they will "merge" in your changes,
这些更改将对使用该项目的所有人都可用。
and they'll be available to everybody who uses the project.
这就是如何在Github上为项目做出贡献，
So, that is how you can contribute to projects on GitHub
使软件更适用于每个人。
and make software better for everybody.
对于Github有任何问题吗？
And, so any questions about GitHub?
明白了，好的。所以，今天的话题就到这里。
Cool, okay. So, that is it for the topics for today.
对于整个讲座有任何问题吗？
Any questions about the lecture overall?
很好，那么在结束之前，
Great, okay, so before - before we finish,
让我简单介绍一下明天的讲座：
a quick description about tomorrow's lecture:
今天是我们认为有趣的和我们觉得应该讨论的所有主题。
so, today was all the topics we thought are interesting, we should talk about,
明天的讲座则是讨论你们觉得有趣的和你们觉得应该要讨论的主题
tomorrow's lecture is gonna be about all the topics you think are interesting and that we should talk about.
明天的讲座将是一个问答环节。
So, tomorrow is going to be  a Q&A lecture.
在今天的讲座之后，我们将通过电子邮件发送一个链接，
And, after today, uh, after the lecture, we'll submit,
您可以通过该链接提交问题供我们回答。
we'll email out a link where you can submit questions for us to answer.
请务必填写，
And so, please go and fill that out,
否则，我们明天将没有太多可谈的内容。
otherwise, we won't have too much to talk about tomorrow.
好的，希望明天在我们的问答讲座中见到您。
Great, so hopefully, see you tomorrow in our Q&A lecture.